howdy this is Jim rut and this is the
Jim rut show
[Music]
this is the gym rut show and this is
your host Jim rut our guest today is
that Voorhees who recently left Google
after eight years as a software engineer
he has some provocative claims about
Google
he claims that Google's been acting
improperly and even illegally with
respect to search results black lists
and more and he has publicly posted a
large repository of what he describes as
Google internal documents to support his
claim this is a special newsmaker
episode of the gym rat show which we
have pulled together very rapidly unlike
on our regular episodes I haven't
researched Zach nor have I reviewed his
documents nor do I have a strong opinion
about the guests expertise and claims as
you will hear in the episode I strongly
disagree with some of Zach's assertions
nonetheless the claims Zach makes about
Google's manipulation of our information
sphere are very disturbing if true and
he does to tie his claims to the
publicly available cache of documents
that he has collected so decide for
yourself with those caveats let's get
started welcome Zach hi how you doing
Jim good to be on the show yeah great to
have you
you've recently come into some public
notoriety I saw that you've put some
documents out from your days at Google
and have been labeled by others have not
yet yourself as the Snowden of Google
what do you think about that as a as a
description I think it's somewhat
accurate
I've been collecting documents from
Google for a few years and the reason
why I collected those documents was
because Google was lying to the American
public about its meddling not only
meddling and search results and YouTube
queries but also meddling in elections
and I could tell that you know I saw
that the Google executives were
perjuring themselves in front of
congressional testimony and I was able
to prove that perjury by seeing that the
things that they said didn't exist
actually existed so they said to
Congress we don't employ blacklist
that's just not something that we do
and I would as I was listening to that I
would go on to the internal search page
and I would type in blacklist and it
would and I would get results and the
one of the results which is really
popular is the YouTube query blacklist
and so that's why I decided to disclose
was to let the American people know what
was really happening what's been the
reaction from Google well Google
attempted to stop me from doing this and
they called a wellness check once they
knew that I was the leaker they called a
wellness check on me and that ended up
escalating because I didn't want to talk
to the police what is it what's a
wellness check for the benefit art bar
listeners that's kind of a new jargon
which I don't think everybody knows tell
us what's a wellness check yeah I didn't
know about it until it will happen to me
but a wellness check is a tip that
someone can call in to the police and
say I don't think this person's well or
I think they're going to do something
and the police then have probable cause
to come to your house and search and
hunt you out until they find you and
then they can ask you a series of
questions like you know are you suicidal
do you plan to hurt yourself have you or
hurt anyone else have you taken the
proper medication you know and it's
these evasive questions
and then once they get the answer that
they want they leave and if you say the
wrong answer
then they detain you and take you into
custody pretty Orwellian sounds
like to me absolutely and I would
suggest anyone who would use such a
thing in bad faith is a moral scoundrel
of the first water absolutely and I
would also say they'd be a very
excellent defendant in a lawsuit maybe
maybe I mean what they did wasn't
illegal you know and they're gonna say
well he we had probable cause because
something that I posted on Twitter which
was I posted a Deadman switch and for
those that don't know what a Deadman
switch when there's a whistleblower
coming forward or someone that
sensitive information and they are
concerned that they're going to be
assassinated then what they can do is
they can tell their adversary hey look
if you kill me then the information that
I have will be disclosed to the public
and so I put a Deadman switch on Twitter
and they use that as a justification to
call in the Wellness Jacky sounds like
bad faith to me people at Google know
what a Deadman switch is right yeah
though I suppose they could probably get
away with playing stupid and who knows
maybe somebody in HR is authentically
stupid as we know that that seems to
happen a lot it seemed to get stupider
the more people join in it's really a
weird phenomenon yeah I remember when
Google had you know almost a monopoly on
the best and the brightest but it's not
clear that it's certainly not the best
anymore but maybe they still have a
pretty good supply of the brightest the
engineers are really smart this is the
weird thing is that the engineers are so
smart and so competent that you expect
that management would be you know the
same but that's not the case it seems
that they're selected more for loyalty
than for competence yeah that's when the
rot starts to set in when people start
kissing up in an organization you know a
good good middle level manager executive
punches up at their bosses and protects
their people right when people start
doing the opposite the rot has set in
that's correct
that's correct and that's what I saw and
I started to see that in 2016 right
after Trump got elected man interesting
so let's go back to what you have seen
as a pattern of egregious behavior at
Google that you believe is has some
unifying strategy behind it and start
start with sort of what you started to
see and what your inferences are from
that behavior and what you think
motivates that behavior yeah so let's go
back to 2016 Trump has won the election
and the executives freaked out and they
have every week there's a weekly meeting
of the executives with all the Google
employees we call it TGIF oddly enough
TGIF happens on Thursday now
but I digress and so at this TGIF the
executives got together and they kind of
had like well Trump got elected let's
let's talk about like what it means and
during this meeting they said some
really crazy stuff and they were saying
that Trump was elected because Russia
hacked our election and Trump got
elected because there's a lot of racism
and hate and misogyny you know in the
general public and that's just a net and
that they didn't realize how bad it was
and so they that's the new reality and
one of the executives even started
crying up on stage yeah I heard that I
remember that I go what the right
yeah so so this was all disclosed so
somebody it wasn't me took a copy of
this video and gave it to Breitbart and
bright bart posted the video and
immediately was like shared with a whole
bunch of people is a huge story and
everyone was was sort of like taken
aback by wow these these people running
Google or really really ideologues so
what happened with all this is I started
to notice that there was some funny
stuff going on with Google and around
December 2016
odd papers started to appear on their
internal networks and I've included a
copy of this in my disclosure to the
public and the name of the pacol is
something along the lines of
psychological induced stress as a result
of algorithmic discrimination and some
people seems broken on their computer
but if you can repair the PDF it's a
it's like 60 pages of psychology musings
about stress of being discriminated
against by algorithms and how to make
that less of an issue and so one of the
things that they said about this is that
the way they could relieve a lot of the
stress of the users was to give them
non-functional buttons and dials that
would pretend to turn some of the
censorship off and that restoring a
user's sense of control would give them
would reduce their
stress caused by all the discrimination
I'm sitting reading this paper going
what the hell what the hell and then
there's weird other weird stuff in there
saying that when people are crowded in
trains that they tend to buy more
products to the to ads and so the paper
describes like how do we simulate this
this sense of crowding so that people
buy more things and I'm just seeing that
go wait a minute like we're we're
getting the best scientists decisions
and mathematicians and psychologists so
that we can increase at engagement by
0.1 percent like what is going on here
so that was that was the beginning of it
right that was the beginning of sort of
like my awakening of what Google was
doing and then we hold on just a second
here I mean isn't their business model
tweaking at engagement by one tenth of
one percent I mean that is the business
of Google right is to hijack people's
attention and then auction it off to the
highest bidder fair enough fair enough
fair enough I guess I just saw it I was
just like wow this is really evil and I
thought at the beginning that welcome
well they're just trying to like it you
know maximize profits for their
shareholders which is their fiduciary
responsibility right so but I I started
goin I started taking myself ooh what's
going on here and what I noticed is the
company started ramping up the crazy
right and the the first thing that they
started doing to really wrap this up was
define the concept of fake news the
executives explained to the company that
fake news was you know a reason that
Trump got elected and so they needed to
protect the American public from all
this fake news and so they started
slapping down on fake news they started
you know crazies papers about like what
fake news is and in that paper they had
an example of what fake news was and in
that example they actually were listing
events that took place okay so I'll give
you an example like Hillary Clinton ran
weapons soup and gauzy to fund Isis to
arm Isis in Syria this is for anybody
that research is just
that this is a conspiracy fact Google's
listing this as an example of fake news
that they need to censor and I'm
thinking why why why are they getting
involved in this politics like why do
they have a dog in the fight but that's
that that's clearly where they were
going and so they started to sort of
sculpt the information landscape and as
I start seeing that they were that they
were what they were filtering I start
investigating will you know what's
what's really going on is this fake news
or is this not fake news and what I
discovered was shocking I discovered
that Hillary could sell off 20% of
America's uranium capacity to Russia and
that there was a book done by this by
Pierre Schweitzer of the enthuse the
Hoover Institute or something like that
one distinct tanks included lays out all
the evidence that this is what happened
and now I see Google at the company is
trying to is try to filter this and I
start seeing that like Wikipedia is
saying that this is a conspiracy theory
even though it seems that it's a
conspiracy fact like it's it's
unimpeachable the evidence is just so
overwhelming and so I start going
through this awakening and I and I can I
continue down and I continue to get
these documents night and I start
figuring out that there's this new
system that they're building called
machine learning fairness Naha that's a
little bit of another Orwellian term
there tell me about that yeah so what
can I say about machine learning
fairness well what they thought was
because there was all this fake news and
there was all this hate and racism
online that Google was going to fix it
through a project called machine
learning fairness and what fairness was
going to do was fairness was well it is
doing and I'm not gonna use the past
tense what it's doing is it's revising
all of their search results and biasing
their YouTube results and it's revising
all of their news so Google search
YouTube and news are like the main
targets of this like ml fairness from a
user perspective and what it does is it
takes in as input training data and it's
it generates these rules which are
applied to comments videos documents
everything that is searching for
figures out how to rank the content
based on how fair it is and what's
really strange is that one of the
documents that they had said like define
like what algorithmic unfairness was and
what they said is like imagine that you
were doing a search for CEOs and most of
the results that pop back were male and
Google's words were if even if this
represented objective reality we could
still classify it as algorithmically
unfair and that we should intervene via
product intervention oh this is when I
said Orwellian in the general sense this
now sounds like it's Orwellian in the
specific sense and that they are trying
to use the word fairness for distorting
reality that's correct
they're looking to to change the nature
of reality to make a better person and
in these documents
you know it's talking about how you know
they can be algorithmically more fair
they're also describing like what they
feel about the user and what they feel
about the user is that the user is
programmed based upon the content that
they're interacting with so news that's
aggregated and goes to the user like
that goes into the users head and then
they programs them and then they turn
around and then they generate content
and this content then contains this
fairness bias whatever you want to call
it and then that generates more content
and that gets aggregated filtered and
then this this the program repeats and
so the fact that they said that people
like us are programmed and that's the
exact words that they used was really
disturbing okay so they think people
like us can be programmed okay well is
this just a one office it's just one
rogue employee but then I saw it in like
another document that was that was
generated and they've done it in a
different way and I was like okay this
is Akademik they think of us as program
programmable units and they're gonna use
their control mechanism in order to
program us and like this is something
like out of a sci-fi novel but I'm
reading it like at my desk and I'm going
oh my god the American people need to
know
what's coming down the pipeline because
if they're gonna program us and that's
their intention then we can't escape
them because they're literally
everywhere I used the Google Chrome
browser to do a google chrome search
when I want to contact someone I use
Gmail half the people that I talk to
have Android phones Google is everywhere
and they've got the scale necessary to
be able to sculpt that information
landscape and if you go against a
narrative maybe Google is gonna turn
evil and then they're going to be able
to know where you are
every single moment of the day it's
really quite frightening when I when I
started to see the whole future unfold
and what was coming down the pipeline
aimed directly at Americans might want
to recap that for our audience see if I
understood what you had to say if I
didn't correct me when I took away from
this is that you believe Google believes
that it is programming its users by the
content it delivers which I'm a
cognitive science perspective probably
has some validity to it actually but the
next step is that they believe they have
some kind of moral obligation or
business obligation or some other
obligation to program people to be
better quote unquote in ways they Google
believe is better describe that your
claim left the center of your claim
that's the center of my claim okay and
in the past we've all generally assumed
and certainly the Google twins page and
Brin have claimed that they are
objective and that they would never ever
try to put a thumb on the scale and you
believe you have evidence that shows
that that is not true yeah now I do I
know I do I have the evidence that
discloses evidence and everyone around
the world is now in a game of
downloading this and dissecting it and
posting it online to Twitter and social
media networks and let me give the let
me give you our audience the address
where you can get this data I'm gonna
give you a caveat though once I give it
to you it's project Veritas dot-com
/ Google -
- dump that gets you to a pile of stuff
go to the everything got zip and
download that ignore their attempt to
peddle some software product which may
or may not even exist and just download
the everything got zip and extract it
that's the best way to get access to
Zacks complete archive and I'm start
looking through it see if what he says
is Veritas the truth right and you know
I will say as I've been looking around I
talked to Pat a little bit it would be
very helpful for people like my audience
which are smart people but often busy
people who don't have time to do this
themselves for someone to craft a well
done narrative document maybe ten pages
that you know tells the story that
you're trying to sell has some excerpts
from these documents and then direct
pointers right to the documents so that
people in twenty minutes can get the
whole story in a in a convincing or not
convincing way I would strongly suggest
you and your friends do that yep yep and
the thing is is that it's coming the
think tanks the people that are
influencers are dissecting this and
making sense of it you know as we speak
one of the people that I urge your
listeners to check out is Robert Epstein
he is the former chief editor of
psychology today and he's made it his
life's mission for the last few years to
prove that Google is engaging in
election meddling and doing it
intentionally and so you know I for
people like Robert Epstein
and you know people like your audience
to be able to see what Google is really
up to because what they say to Congress
and under oath is just not based in
reality what they're doing is they're
they're covering their maliciously
covering for their intentions to engage
in election interference and we know
they have the capability right the book
the age of surveillance capitalism by
Shoshanna Zubov well I have some
quibbles about some of the things in the
book I will say that she landed a 6.0
perfect stick on showing that google
has the power to buy a search result do
lots of news results - do they have a
sense the unlimited power to make the
world appear however they want from
within reason from the perspective of
the Google user so now we have F Zack
saying that not only do they have that
power but they are now using it that's
pretty scary
pretty scary do you have a hypothesis on
why they're doing this so there's these
establishment media players that are
pushing a lot of this racism and this
Russian collusion conspiracy hoax that
was entrusted upon the American public
in the media and my guess is who's ever
been driving them has been also driving
the agenda of Google this has been kinda
in lockstep with the other social media
companies and what's really curious is
that when I go and look at the
stockholders of these companies the
stockholders are similar and actually I
think a lot of cases are almost the same
and like the top 7 and if you look at
the top 7 they have roughly equal
proportions of ownership and so my
question is those people that own it you
know they own all the stock you know are
they the ones driving the agenda and I
suspect that they are and I suspect it's
coordinated because it's not a
coincidence that everyone is wrong about
the same thing at the same time right
like how did everyone get suckered into
this Russian collusion conspiracy hoax
it's it's mind-blowing
and so the fact that this is happening
that also also the culture war with
trying to redefine you know first sex
into gender and then we're talking about
gender and then whenever they refer to
someone's you know sexual identity it's
now referring it to their gender
identity and now gender identity can be
whatever someone decides so now man can
have babies and the fact that this
consensual delusion is being pushed
through all these different channels at
the same time means that it's there's
some coordination going on there's some
agenda that's being pushed and people
need to investigate why this agenda is
being pushed by so many establishment
players at the same time okay I just did
a quick look at the institutional
holders
of top holders outside the insiders at
Google and it's just basically big
pooled capital Vanguard Blackrock tiro
price FM our Northern Trust those do not
seem to me to be a likely source of
ideological influence those people are
strictly chasing yield they're held
accountable by yield by their investors
heck I invested a couple of those so I
doubt that it's the shareholders if
there is a additional force it's
somewhere else
okay let's that's really interesting cuz
i when i saw the vanguard and the
Blackwater appear over and over and over
again my assumption was like well maybe
maybe they're putting pressure on Google
to do the things but you know I'm not
not an expert in institutional investing
so but you might have more visibility
into that I do want to add to that when
Google wit IPO they had a really
different way of structuring the company
with relation to their stock and what
they've done is that they've given and
they've created a couple different
classes of stocks and one of them has
preferential voting rights like I said
something like ten to one which means
that 10% of the stock holders have as
much power as 90 percent of the stock
holders so when they went IPO they had
this like you know note saying that
stock holders aren't going to
necessarily understand all their
opinions but that they have to trust the
executives to make the right decisions
for the long-term goal of the company
well now it's 2019 we know actually what
they meant by that we're gonna take over
the world and we don't want the
stockholders to revolt against us so
we're gonna take away all of their power
do you know many of the tech platform
companies have done that Facebook did an
even more powerful version of it in fact
I just I just pulled it up here on
Google they have three classes of shares
class a one vote per share of which
there are 290 million shares outstanding
this was in 2016 so might be a little
different but not big collects B with 10
votes for share of which there are 52
million so that's 520 million votes
versus the 290 million votes of the
Class A and Class C
with no votes which there are 343
million shares outstanding
so the Class B shareholders ie the
insiders absolutely control the company
there you go that is there you go Class
B so they've created this insider voting
block which has a disproportionate
amount of power and now it's clear that
Google is abandoning their fiduciary
responsibilities to their stockholders
and now the stockholders are stuck
there's nothing they can do about it
right they can sue Google and say no you
can't do this why are you you know
meddling an election theory but they
can't they can't use the powers or
voting and so now what's happening is
that all this flowery language that
Google is used to describe like their
high MIT morals stance just turns out to
be a cover for criminal activity can you
substantiate criminal activity on that
you mentioned earlier but I think it was
probably before we went live and on the
record
the idea that you believe they're guilty
of perjury to Congress can you prove
that I'd love to see you put that
together as a document care I just
created a medium article today proving
that they are engaging in they that
they're engaging in perjury to Congress
so there's a guy by the name of Karen
buta I think I believe he used to work
at GE and I works at Google
and he went before Congress I think of
July and he said we just don't like
Google does not employ blacklists like
it's just not something that we do right
well that's really curious because I've
disclosed to blacklist with my
disclosure and Robert Epstein has
disclosed nine previous blacklist that
he was able to discover through
different information channels so now
we've got a total of like a louder
twelve black lists that have been
disclosed to the public and here we have
you know a representative google
testifying under oath to Congress that
they don't use any black lists well he
may be able to get off on the fact that
he didn't know but of course he should
have caveated that that his knowledge
was not he was either lying which is
certainly possible or he was ignorant
one or the other
yeah but it goes all the way up to the
CEO because the CEO occurred
things similar under under under oath as
well I can't remember exactly what that
quote is but but it was it was it was
around political censorship and that's
just like completely false like you can
go to the Google search engine and you
can type in Trump body-count and will
it'll auto predict like that you're
typing in you know Trump's body count
which is ridiculous there's he doesn't
have one but then you go to Hillary
Clinton and she's got a horrendous body
count list it's like between 45 and 60
people have died under mysterious
conditions around her and so when you
type in Hillary body you know K like
with the C it won't give you any
suggestions will do any predictions and
then now you can cross-reference this
and this is all my article by the way
I'm medium you can cross-reference this
with another service called Trends
Google calm cool calm shows you the real
traffic that people are using in order
to do these searches okay and so what
you can do is you can you can choose
what keyword and then you can like put
it in relation to another keyword so
what I did is I showed that I could put
in Hillary Clinton body count and then
like trust body count and then I
compared those two keywords Trump almost
has nobody searching for Trump body
count okay but Clinton's doesn't show up
under the search results you know if
this was one isolated incidents of
political bias that maybe written off as
some sort of an error but you can do
this to concern if you could do this to
liberal you could do this like men man
you can do this to women and what you're
gonna find is that the search terms that
they're Auto predicting are don't
reflect what users are actually
searching for so the question is why are
all you know what is all this meddling
and search all related to the political
ideology you know if it was like just
you know weird random stuff then you
would think that there would be like no
orientation but this all has a political
orientation and so when
say that they don't use blacklist that's
perjury when they say that they don't
have a political ideology that's perjury
and the thing is is that we know that
they've got political bias because not
only have they interfered in America's
election
they've also interfered in Ireland's
election do the banning of the of the
word or the phrase eighth amendment to
the constitution of Ireland which is
disclosed in the YouTube query blacklist
in my disclosure and also what I just
found out recently is that the Supreme
Court of Brazil ruled that Google
interfered in their election and they
know this because they produced a
contract between Google and the opponent
to the current president of Brazil
interesting first I would like to enter
just say from my own perspective that
the idea that Hillary Clinton has
actually killed 46 people or something I
find to be extremely unlikely and out
there in wackadoodle conspiracy theory
land but nonetheless it is interesting
that but but you're correct that many
people search on that and believe that
while there is no such I didn't believe
it either I may just want to put out I
didn't I was not a conspiracy theorist
in 2016 I didn't believe that Hillary
Clinton was doing a this really bad
stuff but then once I saw that there was
suppression I started looking at it
myself and you know that and Wow one
after another after another I looked
through and there's like a guy maybe was
Vince Foster he was found with two
gunshot wounds to the back of the head
and it was ruled a suicide and so
there's this like criminal mafia element
that's going through and whacking all
these people and it's people that are
just about to come out against the
Clintons and like right before testimony
they get whacked like I remember there
was this one guy that had information
about Hillary and the fraud that
happened with Haiti and he comes to
Florida to like testify and like a
couple days before he testifies he dies
right I'd be careful about adhering to
those things you know there's
part of our brain that loves to build
these conspiracy theories but there's
enough honest reporters out there if
there was anything solid to them I think
we would have seen more about them so my
suggestion would be to go slow on claim
the conspiracies you don't need to do
that to tell your story you know and
think the fact that they have biased the
discussion of conspiracy theories is
enough you know I would not I would
recommend you don't go beyond that at
this point while trying to sell your
story not necessary I mean you're
entitled to your opinion but you know I
done enough investigation where I built
up the what I consider a true model of
how the world works and and this is this
is I mean there are so many things that
the media is not reporting on like no
one's reporting on this Google leak in
the establishment media Fox News isn't
covering at CNN isn't covering at MSNBC
isn't covering it you know there's some
there's a conspiracy going right now
where they're not allowing this story to
reach the American public and they like
Fox News reported on you know the first
leak that or the the first like minor
leak that Project Veritas had they also
reported on great Coppola coming out
there and talking but when this came out
and that and everything got released you
would think that they would at least
talk about it somewhat but it's been a
media blackout so you know if you if one
applies Occam's razor to the whole set
of data that's out there they they can
only come to the conclusion that there
is a that there's some conspiracy that's
going on that reaches all the way into
the media system and that's that's what
I believe and that's what makes the
world simpler and anything that makes
the world a little bit simpler is
something worth investigating I will
that's what I saw that there was nobody
picking this up - one of the reasons I
wanted to have you on my podcast right I
wanted to get yours really appreciate it
you know there's this is how we get it
out there to the people is you know we
this story is one of the biggest stories
of 2019 and everyone that reads it is is
terrified when they see what Google is
really up to and and getting the story
out to the American public is how we
make change because the way to defeat
evil is you just gotta expose it you
know you don't have to worry about
fighting it
you know armor on or swords like he just
got to speak the truth and once people
understand what's happening and then
change will come as a result it's a
force of nature and it is true that the
the big platforms in the mainstream
media no longer have an exclusive on
dissemination of the truth right
we now have collective information
networks of people like podcasters like
bloggers like Twitter tweeters I guess
they call them who can work together not
in a tightly coupled way but
cooperatively to get out stories that
they believe to be true right the
gatekeepers are being bypassed and what
I like to call this as the new Gutenberg
printing press the Gutenberg printing
press changed the information landscape
and caused a completely new form of
society to to come out one rip where
most people were you know became
literate and and we're in that
transition right now because these
networks that people are able to
propagate stories and bypass the
gatekeepers and so I can I can tell my
truth and I can drop you know evidence
of criminal wrongdoing and that goes
directly to the American public and
that's amazing never had something like
that before
absolutely I think it's a great thing
can you give me the title of your medium
posts so I can find it and give people
the link to it I don't have my laptop
next to me at my friend's laptop Kim can
you find me on Twitter because it's one
of the top posts that I have right now
and for your listeners out there my
twitter handle is at perpetual maniac
maniac I like that Zack for he's
perpetual maniac about that
okay mines dupper several maniacs the
letter went to Tulsi gabbard's attorney
and that's a pin tweet it's gonna be two
down from that okay why did Google
suppress medium okay all right
here's the title why did Google suppress
autocomplete for Clinton body count if
you type that phrase and medium into
your window let's see Google isn't some
nefarious way censoring it that would be
very interesting if they were wouldn't
it so let me actually do a cut and paste
here of the title put it into a google
search window and see what comes up okay
it comes up on Y Combinator is on Y
Combinator that story was posted to Y
Combinator that search brings up
something on Y Combinator let's see if
it takes it to your story
it did so yes it's on Y Combinator cool
which means you'll get some traffic
that's an excellent spot so yeah it's on
why the on the Y Combinator wire right
now son that's the anybody else media
all right let me type medium next to it
and see if that brings it up help son
it's interesting nope when I type why
did Google you know title cut and paste
with the word medium it does not bring
it up well I've been told that all my
stuff gets shut up and immediately after
I post it so it doesn't surprise me at
this point let me let me put in your
name and see if that helps in a that is
but it is on what it does come up on Y
Combinator as the first thing nope even
with your name it does not come up in
the top ten on the first page on on
Google which is pretty good when did you
publish it I published it this morning
that may not you know just to be so we
don't over claim it may not yet have
been picked up by the indexer so I mean
the thing is that medium pushes all of
their content directly to the Google
search index live so it should it should
be in within a few seconds so in which
case I would suggest you go to either
Twitter
and perpetual maniac or go to medium and
put in why did Google suppress
autocomplete for the tested on medium
but make sure that works there that
would be really scary but didn't work on
medium medium ok brings you up okay
that's yours now
it says detect when Google is lying
about autocomplete political bias
yeah generator URL and I change the
title so the URL is a little funny it
says the old keyword stuffing in it okay
I like this I'm looking at it quickly
and this is exactly what I had in mind
take the story back it up with excerpts
and tell it in a clear simple way for
people to digest not look that carefully
I'm not gonna say I believe it yet but I
say this is exactly the way I would
encourage you to tell your story in a
way that you know that a person can
follow without having to digest the
whole mass of the data yep and the thing
is is that right now we're in a unique
situation where trends google.com is
still allowed to contradict Google and
my guess is that they haven't figured
out how this little trick and so if the
people that are listening right now want
to test for google bias then
cross-reference the other suggestions
search feature on google with the
tredstep google.com but in the same
exact phrase and you're gonna see what
the real traffic is you're gonna see the
ideological bias in play yeah I love
that objective evidence that people can
make their own eye their own mind up
about whether what Zak is saying here is
really happening and believe he has
presented some compelling evidence but
people can go out and manufacture that
evidence for themselves would be very
interesting if people do find
interesting discrepancies to write their
own quick medium posts one of the
beauties of medium is you can knock
together a post in 15 minutes and have
it up and have some readers yep it's
great what else would you like our
audience to hear about what would you
say some of the more flama Tory
dangerous scary things that you learned
in your in your time at Google right so
I'll talk about the pen tweet that I
have right now my twitter account and
the title if I remember correctly is I
know how insiders
could take down Tulsi gabbard's at
account because I saw how insiders took
down Jordan B Peterson yep yep and so I
want to talk about that story because it
illustrates how Google gets is able to
implement their political agenda let's
hear it what happened with let's let's
go back to the Tulsi Gabbard recall that
she was part of the Democratic debates
and she did a really good job and so
people after the debates decided that
they were going to search for Tulsi
Gabbard well coincidentally Tulsi
gabbard's ad account got suspended for
suspicious activity and I talked to her
lawyer over the phone and who's watching
a 50 million dollar lawsuit and he was
explaining to me about the language that
Google used that it was hard to get an
answer and they said that there was some
suspicious activity related to the
account so they took it down this is the
deactivated as a precautionary measure
now what this meant was that when people
were searching Tulsi Gabbard the only
promoted websites that came up were her
opponents that were trying to capture
her audience and divert it to them well
I've seen this kind of thing before and
I saw it with Jordan B Peters and what's
happening is that there's a security
vulnerability that Google has refused to
patch and that a group of insiders know
about and exploit and the way that it
works is pretty simple let's say that
you've got let's say that Jordan
Peterson's email account was xxx at
gmail.com now you get this email address
and so what you do is that you just say
that you're going to take X X X and
you're gonna replace it with X X Y and
then you make a new account and they do
X X Z and then maybe dou Z X X right and
you create all these different accounts
that are close to the original account
but they differ by like one letter now
you've got an email network now this
email network starts pushing spam to a
bunch of other different email addresses
what happens is that the Google AI
deactivate the spam Network but
surprisingly it will also delete the
original email address not delete it
will deactivate it okay so now the AI
has brought down the target email
address wow that's very very pernicious
and very clever yeah and I know this
because I saw the book report attached
to this because I was pushing the
restoration of Jordan B Peterson's email
account on to you back back onto the
onto the Google system so I was
following this and the report from one
of the operators was oh yeah yeah
there's there's a bunch of spam accounts
that was made with this whole thing and
I was just like oh my god I've got
insider knowledge now I can take down
anyone's account and they're not gonna
know how it works right and so this is a
pattern that I've seen that over and
over and over again is that Google has
some sort of obscure vulnerability and
that a group of insiders gets knowledge
of this vulnerability and then they use
it to take down anyone that they want at
any time and I believe based upon the
pattern that Tulsi gabbard's account was
taken down then I believe that this is
how she was taken down and so I gave I
wrote an open letter to her attorney on
how to do discovery so he could find
this pattern within Google's own bug
database and then use this in order to
further discovery to see if the same
thing was happening with Tulsi gabbard's
accounts now I'm not asserting that this
happened to Tulsi gabbard's account
because I resigned it the company before
this happened but I am asserting that
this is a pattern that I know of that
insiders used to take down accounts that
they target oh that's that's one kind of
scary especially because it's so easy
anybody could do it
and to that if you believe insiders are
doing it that's a gross breach of good
faith it is that's why we need to close
this reason why Google needs to be
audited yep and for those who are
interested in Zak's pretty detailed
story you can find that at minds.com
slash perpetual maniac yep and the title
the title is open letter dear attorney
representing Tulsi Gabbard or you can
find it
his Twitter account that's right it's a
pin post they'll be a pinned for the
rest of this day at least okay all right
what else anything else that you'd like
to tell us yeah I just got it somebody
asked yeah so I want to talk about my
breaking point my breaking point was
when I was like okay it doesn't matter
what the danger is to me I've got to
come forward to the American people was
when I saw Google deleting translation
words out of the Arabic to English
translation dictionary in order to make
a Trump tweet sound crazy and this
craziness was then used by the New York
Times in order to try to invoke the 25th
amendment to remove the President of the
United States
okay so I've disclosed this in this
document dump under the name calf F a
because calf F a was the word that they
deleted and so this background here is
that Trump put to Saudi Arabia around
and he got back around May 25th 2017 and
he returned and he made a tweet and his
tweet was the news is fake
f f/a something to that effect a copay
or something yeah yeah and the calf F a
translation was we will stand up and so
what he's saying is the news is fake but
we will stand up to it and that's a word
that exists in Arabic and one of my
friends said knows Hebrew rule well says
yeah that also exists in Hebrew as well
well the New York Times wrote an article
saying that they had talked to some
experts quote-unquote and that these
experts said that this word was nonsense
and so as a result of that result of
that they declared that it was nonsense
and so as usual that article a design
document was created by one of the
executives at Google saying hey let's
replace the translation with an easter
egg well guess what the easter egg
wasn't ever put in it was just that the
word itself was just deleted and the
problem that they had was the problem
that they had was that they had they
couldn't just delete it once they had to
delete the word twice Jim because what
happened was that the Google AI was
smart enough to do a
netic transliteration of the word and
find a path to cafe in the Arabic
language and so in the the the
implementation notes that I provided
under KF under the CAF FA folder of the
disclosure you're gonna see the
implement the the operation of these
operators as they're trying to delete
this word out and that was just like wow
like okay so now it's not just election
meddling it's also now dishes slash
treasonous behavior that Google is
engaging in in order to remove a sitting
president of the United States that's
when I realized that this is now a
national security issue and so you know
that was the breaking point that's when
I decided that I was going to disclose
this by any means possible interesting
then you believe do you believe that the
audit trail for that behavior will have
been preserved in the Google system I
think that it exists somewhere even if
they try to describe it there's so many
archives and so many data centers that I
believe that they can't scrub all of it
and if they do start scrubbing it then
what's gonna happen is that there's
going to be they're gonna waken more
people up to what Google is doing I
think that a lot of Google employees are
listening to my interviews and they're
becoming awakened to what Google is
doing so if they want to delete it I
mean they can try but I don't think it's
going to be any advantage at this point
do you have a place you'd like other
Google people who are who have evidence
of misdeeds to communicate with you yeah
my my advice to them is that they don't
communicate to me because I know that
I'm being watched right now I mean
that's what I would do if I had the
surveillance system as I would put the
spotlight on me I would tell them to
instead contact Project Veritas and talk
to them they have a professional team
there are professional media
organization and they're the ones that
have the unique capability and integrity
to maintain the discretion of their
whistleblowers and to protect their
identity and to
publish this information only when the
person gives them the okay to do so keep
in mind Project Veritas had most of
these documents that they've disclosed
for over a year and they they lived up
to their end of the bargain they lived
up to their embargo and my advice to
anyone that wants to out Google's
illegal illegal activity or other social
media's illegal activity is to contact
James O'Keefe he is such an amazing
human being other people told me that
and glowing terms and I was like this
guy seems unreal he's like like he's so
loved but then I met him myself and he's
almost like like a hero out of a movie
when when you really get to talk to him
and he is fighting the good fight he's
gonna protect you he's going to help
change the world and make it a better
place so that's what I recommend
everyone to do is contact James O'Keefe
at Project Veritas they've got a submit
links link on their website and that
makes it a lot easier and but I do I do
have to tell people that when they do it
please do it behind a VPN and a tor
browser because the Brout the tor
browser is recognized to be pretty safe
it was developed by the military and the
military doesn't go after its citizens
they go after foreign enemy combatants
so you know if they want to that they
want to submit information do it to
Project Veritas using the tor browser
well thank you sac this has been an
extraordinarily interesting interview
have not been able to have time yet to
read all this myself but I you know the
charges you are making are very serious
and I hope many people take an
opportunity to look into this and and
see if what you're alleging is indeed
going on yeah don't my word for it look
at the documents that I've disposed
that's for all the credibility yes
exactly you are willing to stand behind
your story by having people look at the
data and that that you know increases my
my my willingness to to do further
research in this story rather than just
believe what I say right by the way I
just checked five seconds ago on a
incognito window completely clean and
the title does now
come up as the first entry from medium
why did Google suppress autocomplete for
Clinton body count first result is your
medium article the second is the Y
Combinator news item which will get you
a lot of visibility yeah well you know
the thing is is that there's a lot of
Google people following me and listening
to everything that I say so you know I
just pointed out that they're
suppressing me and then within minutes
it gets unsuppressed so welcome to 2019
where everyone's a conspiracy exact but
maybe we'll ask you to come on back in
in a week or two when the you know when
some clarity starts to come here and we
get a sense of what how Google is gonna
respond to these claims yes yes I would
love to come back on your show and thank
you so much for hosting me on your
podcast it's been an honor and a
pleasure
[Music]
production services and audio editing by
Stanton media lab music by Tom Muller at
modern space music com
[Music]